

JOÃO PAIVA

23 years old



Maringá, Paraná, Brazil



joaovmarcotti@hotmail.com

ABOUT ME

Brazilian and 23 years old. Currently living in Maringá, Paraná, Brazil. Electrical engineer and economics final year student. Golden State Warriors and Corinthians fan. Professionally, I am interested in topics related to finance, data science and machine learning. In my free time, I like to play basketball with friends, play computer games, watch NBA games or prepare some barbecue with my family. My dream? Travel by myself through Scotland, visiting all types of distilleries and drinking different whiskeys.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

Universidade Estadual de Maringá - UEM

Electrical Engineering Bachelor Degree. March 2018 - June 2023.

Universidade Cesumar - UniCesumar

Economics Bachelor Degree. March 2020 - December 2023.

Fundação Getúlio Vargas - FGV

Business Analytics and Big Data Executive MBA. July 2023 - September 2024.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Finance Intern

LIT Concept. June 2021 - July 2021. Cash flow management.

Assistance in corporate separation.

Doors precification.

Inverters Lab Intern

THA Solutions. July 2022 - November 2022.

Fault diagnosis and repair of photovoltaic inverters.

Elaboration of laboratory control sheets.

M&A Intern

Stonecapital. February 2023 - June 2023.

Market analysis.

Valuation by analysis of multiples.

Analysis of financial statements.

Customer prospecting (sell-side).

ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE

Development of an electromyography sensor. April 2019 - April 2021.

Member of the Lapidando Jóias UEM project.

August 2019 - December 2019.

Financial Director of Team Capibaja UEM.

June 2020 - August 2022.

Development of a thermocirculator applied to the Sous Vide culinary technique. March 2021 - April 2023.

Development of an algorithm to rebalance the Ibovespa through Markowitz's Modern Portfolio Theory.

May 2022 - February 2023.

Development and comparison between machine learning models to find the lbovespa's best predictor.

Ago 2023 - Dez 2023.

LANGUAGES

Portuguese - Native. English - Advanced.

SKILLS

Exploratory data analysis

Data cleaning.

Data segmentation.

Heatmap.

Outliers detection.

Variables correlation.

Power BI

Data acquisition

DAX.

Logical functions.

Μ.

Machine Learning

GBoosting.

K Means.

LGBoosting.

Naive Bayes.

Random Forest.

SVM.

XGBoosting.

Microsoft Excel / Google Sheets

Conditional formatting

Data segmentation.

Logical functions.

Pivot table.

PROCH/PROCV.

Python

Matplotlib.

Numpy.

Pandas.

Seaborn.

Deep Learning

GRU.

LSTM.

MLP.

DATA SCIENCE PORTFOLIO

https://github.com/joaopaivaa/DataSciencePortfolio.